Guide to the James Kirkup Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1938-2007; Series II; 54.42; (135 boxes)
  - Poetry
    - Titled Works
      - Throwback, typescript, page proofs, and related material, 1991-1992 (Box 51, Folder 480-485)
      - To the Ancestral North, book jacket, photocopies and clippings, 1983 (Box 51, Folder 486)
      - To The Life
        See: Throwback
      - "Toki," typescript, undated (Box 51, Folder 487)
      - Transmental Vibrations, proofs, printed version and related material, and essays on James Kirkup by K. Kumamoto, 1970s (Box 51, Folder 488-489)
        Accompanied by "Private Parts," typescript
      - "Utakai Hajune," drafts, holograph, 1997 (Box 51, Folder 490)
      - Visions and Adventures: Poems for Young People, typescript, undated (Box 52, Folder 491)
      - "Vivienne at Rodwell" materials, photos and T. S. Eliot cuttings, 1970? (Box 52, Folder 492)
      - What Shall I Bring You?, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 52, Folder 493)
      - White Shadows, Black Shadows
        - Typescripts and associated correspondence, 1969-1970, undated (Box 53, Folder 494-498)
        - Printed version (copies) and photographs, 1970, undated (Box 53, Folder 499-502)
        - On White Shadows, offprint, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 503)
      - Words for Contemplation, original typescript and carbon, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 504-506)
      - Zen Contemplations
        - Drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 54, Folder 507-508)
        - Printed version and associated material, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 509)
    - Untitled Works
      Arranged roughly chronologically.
      - Poems, holograph, 1939-1940 (Box 55, Folder 510)
      - Poems, holograph and typescript, 1939-1941 (Box 55, Folder 511)
      - French Poems (by James Kirkup and translations), typescript, 1939-1940, undated (Box 55, Folder 512)
      - Early Poems, 1940-42 (exclusively war), typescript and typescript carbon, 1940-1942 (Box 55, Folder 513)
      - Early Poems, holograph and typescript, 1940-1942 (Box 55, Folder 514-515)
      - "Old poems," typescript, 1943, undated (Box 55, Folder 516-519)
      - Poems, drafts, holograph and typescript, 1940s? (Box 56, Folder 520)
      - Early Poems, holograph and typescript, 1940s (Box 56, Folder 521)
      - "Poems from Buffalo", 1940s-1950s (Box 56, Folder 522-527)
        "These are the poems and early drafts I asked Library of Buffalo to return to me"
        "Filed by University of Buffalo in pink papers, with three lists of titles in librarian's hand"
      - Poems, drafts and Newspapers ("Review of O.C."), 1940s-1950s (Box 57, Folder 528)
      - "Various unused or incomplete poems," typescript, 1946, 1959 (Box 57, Folder 529)
      - "Early children's poems," typescript, 1950s (Box 57, Folder 530)
      - "Child and adult poems," drafts, holograph and typescript, 1984-1985 (Box 57, Folder 531)
      - "Children's poems, Pasolini," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 57, Folder 532)
      - "New Children's Book," typescript, undated (Box 57, Folder 533)
      - Poetry Anthology, drafts, correspondence and related material, 1968 (Box 57, Folder 534)
      - "Songs and Poems," holograph and typescript, undated (Box 57, Folder 535)
      - New Poems, typescript, 1969, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 536)
      - Poems, Nagoya, typescript, 1970 (Box 57, Folder 537)
      - Poems written by "Andrew James," (pseudonym for James Kirkup and Andrew Oerke), typescript (copy), 1970 (Box 57, Folder 538)
      - "New and Old Haiku," holograph and typescript, 1970-1991 (Box 58, Folder 539)
      - Poems ("Includes both final and unfinished"), typescript and clippings, 1974-1975 (Box 58, Folder 540)
      - Translations of Kirkup's poetry into Welsh by Poet Carrellio, typescript and related letter, 1976 (Box 58, Folder 541)
      - Poems, drafts and signed copies, 1977-1979 (Box 58, Folder 542)
      - Various poems, essays and letters, drafts, holograph and typescript, 1978-1980 (Box 58, Folder 543)
      - Poems, manuscript and typescript, 1979-1980, undated (Box 58, Folder 544-547)
      - New poems (children's poems), typescript, 1984 April (Box 59, Folder 548)
      - Rough drafts of poems, typescript, 1985, undated (Box 59, Folder 549)
      - "Poem drafts," holograph and typescript, 1986-1987 (Box 59, Folder 550)
      - Haiku drafts, typescript, 1986-1987 (Box 59, Folder 551-552)
      - "Recent Poems and Songs / Children," drafts, typescript, 1988 (Box 59, Folder 553)
      - "New Poems," drafts, typescript, 1989 (Box 59, Folder 554)
      - "Recent poems," typescript, 1994 (Box 59, Folder 555)
      - New poems and drafts, typescript, 1994 October (Box 59, Folder 556)
      - "Poem drafts and typescripts", 1994-1995, undated (Box 59, Folder 557)
      - "Poems in corrected drafts," holograph and typescript, 1995 (Box 59, Folder 558)
      - Tanka (including translations), holograph and typescript, 1995-1996 (Box 60, Folder 559-565)
      - Poem drafts and corrected typescripts, 1999-2000 (Box 60, Folder 566)
      - New Poems, holograph and typescript, 2001 September (Box 60, Folder 567)
      - "Past poems for reconsideration," drafts, 2002 (Box 60, Folder 568)
      - "Recent Poems," holograph and typescript, 2003 (Box 60, Folder 569)
      - Poems, drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 61, Folder 570-575)
      - Poems, including "Endoscopy" and "Rise, Decline and Fall of the Sunflower," typescript (copy), undated (Box 61, Folder 576)
      - Poems and short stories written by James Kirkup under the pseudonyms Taeko Kawai and Jun Honda, typescript, undated (Box 61, Folder 577)
      - Children's poems, drafts, undated (Box 61, Folder 578)
      - Children's poems, printed versions and related material, undated (Box 61, Folder 579)
      - Collection of Poems including "War Love Peace," and "Taking of A Likeness," typescript, undated (Box 61, Folder 580-581)
      - Cross Poems, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 61, Folder 582)
      - Poems, drafts ("Downs School"), undated (Box 62, Folder 583)
      - Poems, drafts, including "The Hills" and "Prodigal Son", undated (Box 62, Folder 584)
      - Poems including "The Sleeping Beauty," typescript, undated (Box 62, Folder 585)
      - Poems, including "Northern Names," holograph and typescript, undated (Box 62, Folder 586)
      - Poems in French, typescript, undated (Box 62, Folder 587)
      - "Whale" poems, printed versions (copies), undated (Box 62, Folder 588)
      - Poems and translations, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 62, Folder 589-592)
      - Haiku drafts, undated (Box 62, Folder 593)
  - Works of Prose
    Works of Prose are organized under two headings: Titled Works and Untitled Works.
    Novels, short stories, autobiography, travel writing, and language and culture textbooks are filed here.
    - Titled Works
      - After the Fallout / Whatever Next?, typescript (and copy), undated (Box 63, Folder 594-595)
      - "Albert Cossery," draft and related material, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 596)
      - Another Side of Joe, typescript, undated (Box 63, Folder 597)
      - Aspects of the Short Story, introduction and notes, typescript, undated (Box 63, Folder 598)
      - The Asymmetrical Archipelago: Parallels & Paradoxes, typescript (copy), undated (Box 63, Folder 599)
      - At Home In The East, drafts, typescript and carbon, undated (Box 64, Folder 600-603)
      - At Home in the Philippines, typescript, undated (Box 64, Folder 604)
      - Background to British Literature and Life, typescript, 1973 (Box 65, Folder 605-606)
      - Bangkok: Portrait of a City, typescript and carbon, and proofs, undated (Box 65, Folder 607-609)
      - Banipal: Magazine of Modern Arab Literature, essays, typescript and printed versions, 2004-2005 (Box 65, Folder 610)
      - "The British Lady and Gentleman," typescript carbon and related material, undated (Box 66, Folder 611)
      - Candle in the Heavens, drafts, holograph and typescript, and related correspondence, 1955 (Box 66, Folder 612)
      - "Charles Trenet," typescript and clippings, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 613)
      - "Communication in English speech and writing," and "How to improve the teaching of English," typescripts, undated (Box 66, Folder 614)
      - A Crack in the Wall (preface by James Kirkup), computer printout, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 615-616)
      - "Dear Old Joe," manuscript and typescript (Box 66, Folder 617)
      - Dictionary of National Biography: JK on Elias Canetti (Box 66, Folder 618)
      - Diversions, (Prologue to Festschrift), typescript and related images, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 619-620)
      - Doing It, by Felix Liston (pseudonym for Kirkup), typescript, 1989 (Box 67, Folder 621-622)
      - Encounters, photographs, 1979 (Box 67, Folder 623)
      - England Revisited: My London, typescript carbon, undated (Box 67, Folder 624)
      - English Literature, Parts I and II, typescript, undated (Box 67, Folder 625-626)
      - Europe, fragment of typescript, undated (Box 67, Folder 627)
      - Everyday English Idioms
        - Drafts, typescript, and related correspondence, 1991 (Box 67, Folder 628-629)
        - Proof, 1991 (Box 67, Folder 630)
      - Everyday English Proverbs, typescript, undated (Box 67, Folder 631)
      - Everyday English Superstitions, typescript carbon and printed version (copy), undated (Box 67, Folder 632)
      - Father of the Man (Box 67)
        See: I, Of All People
      - Filipinescas, typescript, undated (Box 68, Folder 633-638)
      - "Flower of the Sun: A radio biography of Vincent van Gogh," holograph, undated (Box 69, Folder 639)
      - "A Fragment by Chemier," holograph, 1939-1940 (Box 69, Folder 640)
      - Gaijin on the Ginza, typescript and copy, 1987, undated (Box 69, Folder 641-643)
      - Gestes a la mer by Feyyaz Fergar, introduction by James Kirkup, notes, undated (Box 69, Folder 644)
      - "A Good Grey Poet," introduction to a volume of poems by Tsutomu Fukuda, typescript, 1992 (Box 69, Folder 645)
      - "Harmonie du Soir," typescript, 1939 (Box 69, Folder 646)
      - "Haro, Radjerd Kysbrig-san," by James Kirkup, printed version, 1989 (Box 69, Folder 647)
      - "Hearn in My Heart," typescript, undated (Box 69, Folder 648)
      - The Heavenly Mandate, typescript, undated (Box 69, Folder 649-650)
      - "Hofmannsthal on Hearn," typescript and printed version, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 651)
      - Hong Kong and Macao (Cities of the World Series), holograph, undated (Box 69, Folder 652)
      - Hotel Novelty (an unfinished novel), typescript (copy), undated (Box 70, Folder 653)
      - How I Discovered America
        - Typescript, accompanied by letter from J.M. Dent & Sons, 1971, undated (Box 70, Folder 654-655)
        - Related material, undated (Box 70, Folder 656-660)
      - "How to improve the teaching of English," typescript, undated (Box 70, Folder 661)
      - "Humour is International" and "Dracula" ("page-proof reading copies for recordings"), undated (Box 70, Folder 662)
      - I, A Stranger, typescript, undated (Box 70, Folder 663-664)
      - "I Am Frankenstein's Monster!!!," second carbon (Box 71, Folder 665)
      - I, Of All People / Father of the Man
        - Typescripts and copies, 1980s, undated (Box 71, Folder 666-670)
        - Typescripts and copies (continued), 1980s, undated (Box 72, Folder 671-676)
        - Correspondence, clippings and other related material, 1955-1980s, undated (Box 73, Folder 677-684)
        - Proof, 1988 February (Box 73, Folder 685)
        - Reviews, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 686)
        - Japanese translation of selected passages by Akiko Takemoto, printout, undated (Box 73, Folder 687)
      - Insect Summer (Box 73)
        - Drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 74, Folder 688-694)
        - Proofs, undated (Box 75, Folder 695-698)
        - Correspondence, images and other related material, 1971, undated (Box 75, Folder 699)
        - Printed version (copy), 1989 (Box 75, Folder 700)
      - "The Invisible Poet," typescript, 1969 (Box 75, Folder 701)
      - Japan Behind the Fan, proof, corrected, undated (Box 76, Folder 702)
      - Japan in the World, typescripts, proofs and correspondence with publisher Kirihara Shoten, 1990 (Box 76, Folder 703)
      - "Japan Industrial," holograph, undated (Box 76, Folder 704)
      - "Japan Journal," typescript and related material, 1982-1983 (Box 76, Folder 705-706)
      - Japan Without the Fan, typescript, undated (Box 76, Folder 707)
      - Japanewspeak, typescript and related material, 1980s (Box 77, Folder 708-712)
      - Journey To A Microsecond
      - The Joys of Japan (complete ZARE series), printed version (copy), undated (Box 77, Folder 713)
      - "Kinki is as Kinki Does," typescript, undated (Box 77, Folder 714)
      - "Language, Literature, and Life," printed version and photocopies, undated (Box 77, Folder 715-716)
      - "Les Armants Terribles," holograph and typescript, 1939?-1940? (Box 78, Folder 717-718)
      - The Little Man and the Little Miss, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 78, Folder 719)
      - "Look East, Look West, " typescript carbon (textbook for Turumi Shoten), 1977 (Box 78, Folder 720)
      - Look, Stranger ("Impressions of English Life"), drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 78, Folder 721-723)
      - Love, the Beloved Republic: A Memoir of Morgan Forster, typescripts, 1970 (Box 78, Folder 724-725)
      - The Love of Others / Births, Marriages and Deaths
        - Draft, typescript, 1959 (Box 78, Folder 726)
        - Correspondence, undated (Box 78, Folder 727)
      - Me All Over: Memoirs of a Misfit
        - Typescript "In memory of Joe and Nancy", undated (Box 78, Folder 728)
        - Typescript and letter to Miss Brazil, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 729)
        - Typescript, undated (Box 78, Folder 730)
        - Typescript, "A memoir of misspent maturity", undated (Box 79, Folder 731-733)
        - Typescript, "with working notes on final chapter", undated (Box 79, Folder 734-735)
        - Typescript, "Part Two, Gay Go Up, Gay Go Down", undated (Box 79, Folder 736-737)
        - Typescript, "Francis King-Permission", undated (Box 80, Folder 738-739)
        - Photographs, ephemera, clippings, 1991, undated (Box 80, Folder 740-743)
        - Image for "Misfit" cover, undated (Box 80, Folder 744)
        - Book jacket, undated (Box 80, Folder 745)
      - Modern American Myths, typescript and related material, 1980s (Box 80, Folder 746-747)
      - "The Moment Forseen," draft, holograph and typescript, 1998 (Box 80, Folder 748)
      - "Murder in Miniature" (short story), holograph, 1938? (Box 80, Folder 749)
      - Mutual Misunderstandings, typescript and copy, 1991 (Box 81, Folder 750-751)
      - The Mystery and Magic of Symbols, typescript, undated (Box 81, Folder 752)
      - "News and Views," typescript and holograph, undated (Box 81, Folder 753)
      - "No More Hiroshimas"
        - Correspondence and contracts, 1995 (Box 81, Folder 754)
        - Printed version (copy) and related material, undated (Box 81, Folder 755)
      - "Novels to go to sleep by" (on Kenzaburo Oe), typescript, 1994 (Box 81, Folder 756)
      - Object Lessons, proof, 1990 (Box 81, Folder 757)
      - The Only Child
        - Japanese translation by Akiko Takemoto, "First draft. Reproductions", undated (Box 81, Folder 758)
        - "On a Picture Taken in Childhood," typescript, 1968 (Box 81, Folder 759)
      - The Other Boy And I by Edward Raeburn (pseudonym for James Kirkup), typescript and copy, 1991 (Box 82, Folder 760-763)
      - "Pay-Night," typescript, 1939?-1940? (Box 82, Folder 764)
      - "Peak Visions of Magritte," printed version, 1992 (Box 82, Folder 765)
      - "People Like Us" (Prelude), typescript, undated (Box 82, Folder 766)
      - A Poet Could Not But Be Gay
        - Drafts, typescript (copies), undated (Box 83, Folder 767-768)
        - Reviews, clippings, 1991 (Box 83, Folder 769)
      - The Poet's Voice, drafts, typescript, undated (Box 83, Folder 770-773)
      - Portraits and Souvenirs, typescript, 1987 (Box 84, Folder 774)
      - "The Present of Forever," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 84, Folder 775)
      - Queens Have Died Young and Fair
        - Draft, typescript, 1991 (Box 84, Folder 776-777)
        - Draft, typescript (copy), accompanied by clippings, 1991 (Box 84, Folder 778)
        - Draft, holograph and typescript, accompanied by clippings, 1991 (Box 84, Folder 779-780)
        - Drafts, typescript (copies), undated (Box 85, Folder 781-782)
        - Book jacket, undated (Box 85, Folder 783)
      - "Reginald Horace Blyth," drafts, typescript, and related correspondence, 1990s (Box 85, Folder 784-787)
      - "The Rising ¥eneration," typescript, undated (Box 86, Folder 788)
      - Robata in English, typescript and handwritten notes, undated (Box 86, Folder 789)
      - "Robin Skelton -- A Student at Leeds University," typescript and related correspondence, 2006 (Box 86, Folder 790)
      - "The Romance that was Rome," typescript and related correspondence, 1990, undated (Box 86, Folder 791-793)
      - Russia Inside Out, typescript and correspondence, 1968 (Box 86, Folder 794)
      - Scenes from British Life (Seibido textbook), typescript and copy, 1988 (Box 86, Folder 795-796)
      - Search For Love
        - Draft, holograph (notebook), undated (Box 87, Folder 797)
        - Typescripts, 1949, undated (Box 87, Folder 798-802)
      - Self and Non-Self: The Mirror Mind, typescript (copy), undated (Box 87, Folder 803)
      - The Separated Heart, typescript, 1947? (Box 88, Folder 804)
      - The Shaping of Poetry (Teacher's Handbook), undated (Box 88, Folder 805)
      - Snakes in the Grass, by Makoto Tamaki, introduction by James Kirkup, draft, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 88, Folder 806)
      - "So Speaking As I Think," printed version, 1975 (Box 88, Folder 807)
      - "Some Considerations on the Translation of Poetry," typescript (copy), 1985? (Box 88, Folder 808)
      - "Some Impressions of Japanese Kokeshi," typescript, undated (Box 88, Folder 809)
      - Something for Everybody, typescript and copy, 1984-1989 (Box 88, Folder 810-812)
      - Sorrows, Passions, and Alarms, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 88, Folder 813)
      - Sorrows, Passions, and Alarms, holograph and typescript (continued), undated (Box 89, Folder 814)
      - Sour Sweet by Timothy Mo, introduction by James Kirkup, typescript and associated material, 1989 (Box 89, Folder 815)
      - The Sports of Love
        - Drafts, typescript, undated (Box 89, Folder 816-817)
        - Typescripts (bound copies) and clippings, 1991, undated (Box 89, Folder 818-820)
        - Typescripts (bound copies) and clippings (continued), 1991, undated (Box 90, Folder 821)
      - Streets of Asia, drafts, holograph, typescript, and typescript carbon, undated (Box 90, Folder 822-823)
      - These Horned Islands
        - Notes and clippings, undated (Box 91, Folder 824-825)
        - Draft, "I, incomplete typescript", undatd (Box 91, Folder 826)
        - Draft, "II, incomplete typescript", undated (Box 91, Folder 827-828)
        - Draft, "complete typescript", undated (Box 91, Folder 829-830)
        - Copyright and financial records, 1969, 1990 (Box 91, Folder 831-832)
        - Photographs and related materials, undated (Box 91, Folder 833)
        - Review of Japan ohne Fächer, German translation of These Horned Islands, clipping, undated (Box 91, Folder 834)
      - "Tightrope and Seesaw," typescript, undated (Box 91, Folder 835)
      - To Be a Stranger
        - Clippings and other related material, 1995 (Box 92, Folder 836)
        - Drafts, typescript, 1995 (Box 92, Folder 837-839)
      - "To Hell with Percy," and other essays, typescript carbon, undated (Box 92, Folder 840)
      - "Tokyo" (incomplete manuscript), holograph, undated (Box 92, Folder 841)
      - Tropic Temper
        - Publisher's complete typescript, undated (Box 92, Folder 842-843)
        - Related material: house in Kuala Lumpur, cuttings about Majestic Hotel, 1962 (Box 92, Folder 844)
      - TV Talk-BBC, typescript, undated (Box 93, Folder 845)
      - "Two Old Japan Hands" / Ralph Hodgson, draft and related material, 1970, undated (Box 93, Folder 846)
      - "The way I see America," typescript, 1969 November 16 (Box 93, Folder 847)
      - The Westovian, printed versions, 1929-1931 (Box 93, Folder 848)
      - Whatever Next?, typescript, undated (Box 93, Folder 849)
      - Zen Kyoto, proof, undated (Box 93, Folder 850-851)
    - Untitled Works
      Related material filed under this heading is grouped together but is otherwise unarranged.
      - Autobiographical files
        Notes, drafts, clippings, correspondence, photographs and ephemera compiled by Kirkup when researching several volumes of autobiographical writings.
        - "Autobiographical associations," typescript and associated material, 1992, undated (Box 94, Folder 852)
        - Material for Autobiographies, 1940-1960 (Box 94, Folder 853)
        - Autobiographies, notes and typescript, undated (Box 94, Folder 854-855)
        - "Spain, Sweden," clippings and drafts of poems, undated (Box 94, Folder 856)
        - "Auto III," notes and related material, undated (Box 94, Folder 857-858)
        - "Auto III, sketches for poems", 1960s (Box 94, Folder 859)
        - Autobiographies III and IV, "spare pages and cuttings", 1988-1990, undated (Box 95, Folder 860)
        - "Autos III & IV," research files (correspondence, clippings and other documents), 1960s (Box 95, Folder 861-863)
        - "Auto IV," unused materials, correspondence and ephemera, 1970s (Box 95, Folder 864)
        - "Auto III, French translation," notes and drafts, undated (Box 95, Folder 865)
        - "Auto III," clippings and other research material, 1950s-1970s (Box 95, Folder 866-867)
        - "Auto III," clippings and other research material (continued), 1950s-1970s (Box 96, Folder 868-873)
        - "Auto III," Fred and Muriel Lawson, sketches, notes and correspondence, 1950s (Box 96, Folder 874-875)
        - "Auto III," Japan, undated (Box 96, Folder 876)
        - "Notes for Auto III", undated (Box 96, Folder 877)
        - "Auto I-IV, extra materials", undated (Box 97, Folder 878)
        - "Auto VI, cuttings on censorship and blasphemy", 1990s (Box 97, Folder 879)
      - Biographical files, 1950s-1980s (Box 97, Folder 880-884)
        Correspondence, clippings and manuscript material related to biographical essays and entries about James Kirkup.
      - "Blasphemy" files
        - "Books, pamphlets, clippings, etc.: Blasphemy", 1978-1990, undated (Box 97, Folder 885-886)
        - "Correspondence about my 'blasphemous' poem", 1997 (Box 98, Folder 887)
        - "A Case of Blasphemous Obscenity," by R. Davis, typescript (copy), 1998 (Box 98, Folder 888)
        - Notes concerning Mary Whitehouse and the 1977 blasphemy case, including "On the Death of Mrs W.," poem, typescript, signed, 2001 (Box 98, Folder 889)
      - British Broadcasting Corporation radio scripts, undated (Box 98, Folder 890)
      - Novel themes, clippings and notes, 1991 April (Box 98, Folder 891)
      - Short stories, drafts, typescript, 1940s-1950s, undated (Box 98, Folder 892-894)
      - Short stories, drafts, typescript (continued), 1940s-1950s, undated (Box 99, Folder 895-897)
      - "Book on U.S.A. (never published)," typescript, undated (Box 99, Folder 898-899)
      - Urban Legends: New Material, 1990s (Box 99, Folder 900)
      - "Movies Book," typescript and associated material, 1985, undated (Box 99, Folder 901)
      - "Projected book on Japan," photographs and captions, undated (Box 99, Folder 902-903)
      - Young people (essay themes), clippings, 1980s (Box 100, Folder 904)
      - "Britain: New material," typescript (copy), undated (Box 100, Folder 905)